<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Blog</title>
    <link>https://jmcelwa.in/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jmcelwa.in/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Restoring S3 Suspend to X1 Carbon (6th Gen) on Linux</title>
      <link>https://jmcelwa.in/posts/x1c-acpi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmcelwa.in/posts/x1c-acpi/</guid>
      <description>My current laptop is the second in the X1 Carbon lineup I&amp;rsquo;ve owned. In general, it&amp;rsquo;s been painless running Linux. However, in this current iteration, I was surprised to find that suspend-to-ram functionality isn&amp;rsquo;t enabled in UEFI. Apparently, Lenovo is catering to a new Microsoft sleep state Windows Modern Standby that allows for devices to be more easily woken up when in deep sleep (think mobile phones). There&amp;rsquo;s a long thread on the Arch forums about this, and I was able to successfully follow this blog post in order to patch my system, with a few exceptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins X and Managed Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://jmcelwa.in/posts/jenkins-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmcelwa.in/posts/jenkins-x/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes vs Serverless We&amp;rsquo;ve been using Openshift, Red Hat&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;distribution&amp;rdquo; of Kubernetes, for over a year now. Although there are definitely pain points with learning an API with such a large surface area, in general my experience as an application developer has been really positive. Although our biggest gains were effects of moving off an old school Spring/Tomcat WAR deployment model to Docker and Spring Boot, Openshift itself is packaged really nicely and seems to have a lot of commitment from Red Hat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Rust</title>
      <link>https://jmcelwa.in/posts/learning-rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmcelwa.in/posts/learning-rust/</guid>
      <description>Learning Rust as an Application Developer I don&amp;rsquo;t have a CS degree, and was never forced to sit through an operating systems class. I feel pretty comfortable reading C, and have used Linux as my daily driver for years, so I&amp;rsquo;m not a total novice when it comes to systems, but it&amp;rsquo;s definitely outside of my development experience, which has mainly been with Java and to a lesser extend JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>